

#### **PROFILE**

Intend to enhance and strengthen my knowledge and experience in any area related to my field of specialization and to work with leading corporate of hi-tech environment with committed & dedicated people, which will help me to explore myself fully and realize my potential.

#### CONTACT

#### PHONE

9712586829, 9923557841

#### WEBSITE:

https://linkedin.com/in/vijay-raval-20981561

https://facebook.com/rvr.vijay

#### **EMAIL:**

vijayraval406@gmail.com vijayraval406@yahoo.com

#### **HOBBIES**

Reading Travelling Music

#### **LANGUAGES**

English Hindi Gujarati

# VIJAYKUMAR RAVAL

# SUPPORT ANALYST

#### **EDUCATION**

Hasmukh Goswami College of Eng. Ahmedabad, Gujarat.

2009 - 2012

I have completed B.E. Computer in Gujarat Technological University.

V.P.M.P. Polytechnic. Gandhinagar, Gujarat.

2006 - 2009

I have completed Diploma C.E. in Technical Education Board.

R.C. College of Commerce, Ahmedabad, Gujarat.

2002 - 2006

I have completed Bachelor of Commerce in Gujarat University.

Sharda Higher Secondary High School, Ahmedabad, Gujarat.

2002 - 2002

I have completed H.S.C in Gujarat Higher Secondary Education Board.

Shri Kailash Shikshan Tirth Higher Secondary School, Ahmedabad, Gujarat.

2000 - 2000

I have completed S.S.C in Gujarat Secondary Education Board.

#### **PROJECTS**

Hasmukh Goswami College of Eng. Ahmedabad, Gujarat. Intranet Mailing System

03/2012 - 05/2012

**Duration:** Degree (8th Semester) in Computer Engineering.

Language: JSP Servlet with MySQL

**Description:** This is home based project completed in "HGCE College". Intranet is a provide network inside a company or organization, which uses software like that used on the internet, but is for internal use only, and is not accessible to the public. Companies use Intranets to manage projects, provide employee information, distribute data and information etc.

Hasmukh Goswami College of Eng. Ahmedabad, Gujarat. Intranet Mailing System

09/2011 - 11/2011

**Duration:** Degree (7<sup>th</sup> Semester) in Computer Engineering.

Language: JAVA JSP with MySQL

**Description:** This is home based project completed in "HGCE College".

Customer Relationship Management (CRM) is a system for managing a Company's interactions with current and future customers. It often involves using technology to organize, automate, and synchronize sales, marketing, Customer service, and technical support.

## Silver Touch Technologies Limited, Ahmedabad, Gujarat.

Associate EDD 03/2009 – 05/2009

**Duration:** Diploma (6<sup>th</sup> Semester) in Computer Engineering.

Language: JAVA with Applet

Description: This project completed by "SILVER TOUCH Tech. Ltd."

Company in "VPMP Polytechnic"

The Chat Server Application project performs an operation to chatting client and admin who can send the message to each other in this project.

#### **PROFESSIONAL TRAINING**

#### Innovatus Technologies, Pune, Maharashtra. JAVA Developer Training 12/2019 – 03/2020

Innovatus Technologies is one of the Best Java Training Institute in Pune that offers no specific eligibility criteria for learning a high-level programming language. Any learner can opt for this Java Coaching class. It works great for working professionals who want to move on with this technology and want to consider a Java programming course for upgraded purposes.

Training in Various components of JAVA and application life cycle resources.

Training in Core JAVA (OOP's concept, Object and Classes, Packages and Interfaces, Exception Handling, String, Collection Framework, Multithreading) and Advance JAVA (Java Swing, JDBC, Servlet, JSP, Spring and Hibernate).

Using the MySQL database for creating JAVA Web applications. Working with Eclipse IDE tool.

#### Web Mastro I.T. Pvt. Ltd., Ahmedabad, Gujarat. Android Developer Trainee 09/2014 – 04/2015

Training in Various components of Android and application life cycle resources. Creating Menus and Layouts in Android. Using the SQLite database for creating Android applications.

Working with Android Studio tool.

Also work in Live project and Code and Designing interactive apps with multimedia.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### TransPerfect Solution India Pvt. Ltd., Pune, Maharashtra. Support Analyst

07/2015 - Present

Import, Export oracle data to other Databases.

SQL operations like create, update, append, delete and migrate. Continuous growth, R&D and development in Electronic Discovery process (e-Discovery).

Production specialist with accuracy and timeline.

Manual testing, implementation and suggestions on new arrival applications.

#### Mangalam InfoTech Pvt. Ltd., Ahmedabad, Gujarat. Associate EDD 02/2013 – 01/2015

Development in Electronic Discovery process (e Discovery). Import, Export oracle data to other database, SQL operation like

create, update, delete, append and migrate.

Demonstrate accuracy, overview quality assurance process of documents/data load files presented to client.

Ensure that products and services are delivered to the client's satisfaction on time.

### **SKILLS**

C, C++, JAVA, Advance JAVA, HTML, JSP, CSS, JAVA Script, MySQL, Oracle, Photoshop.